The Machines Will Rise.
Terminator 3: Rise of the Machines is a action, thriller,
science fiction film directed by Jonathan Mostow.
It's been 10 years since John Connor saved Earth from Judgment Day, and he's now
living under the radar, steering clear of using anything Skynet can trace.
That is, until he encounters T-X, a robotic assassin
ordered to finish what T-1000 started.
Good thing Connor's former nemesis, the Terminator, is back to
aid the now-adult Connor … just like he promised.
The Terminator, played by Arnold Schwarzenegger.
John Connor, played by Nick Stahl.
Kate Brewster, played by Claire Danes.
T-X, played by Kristanna Loken.
Dr. Peter Silberman, played by Earl Boen.
Robert Brewster, played by David Andrews.
Terminator 3: Rise of the Machines is a 2003 science fiction action film, the third installment
in the Terminator franchise and a sequel to Terminator 2: Judgment Day (1991).
It was directed by Jonathan Mostow and stars Arnold
Schwarzenegger, Nick Stahl, Claire Danes, and Kristanna Loken.
In its plot, the malevolent artificial intelligence Skynet sends a T-X (Loken)—a highly advanced Terminator—back in time to ensure the
rise of machines by killing top members of the future human resistance as John Connor's (Stahl) location is unknown.
The resistance sends back a reprogrammed T-850 (Schwarzenegger) to
protect John and his future wife, Kate Brewster (Danes).
While Terminator creator James Cameron was interested in directing the third
film, he ultimately had no involvement with Terminator 3.
Vajna and Mario Kassar, who had produced Terminator 2: Judgment Day through their company Carolco Pictures, obtained the
rights for the franchise through both Carolco's liquidation auction and negotiations with producer Gale Ann Hurd.
In 1999, Tedi Sarafian was hired to write the first draft of the script.
Mostow joined the project as director in 2001, and he brought on John
Brancato and Michael Ferris to rewrite Sarafian's script.
The $187 million budget included a $5 million salary for Mostow
and a record $30 million salary for Schwarzenegger.
Filming took place in California from April to September 2002.
Industrial Light & Magic and Stan Winston created the special
effects, as they did for the previous film.
Terminator 3: Rise of the Machines premiered at the Mann Village Theater in Westwood, Los
Angeles, on June 30, 2003, and was released on July 2, 2003, by Warner Bros.
Pictures in North America.
The film was rolled out overseas throughout the next few months, with Columbia
Pictures overseeing the bulk of the international distribution.
It received generally positive reviews and earned $433.4 million worldwide,
finishing its theatrical run as the seventh-highest-grossing film of 2003.
The film was also used to mark Schwarzenegger's formal entry into politics, having
been speculated to be a vehicle for his 2003 gubernatorial run.
A sequel, Terminator Salvation, was released in 2009.
The film explores themes of man vs machine, artificial intelligence
(a.i.), saving the world, leather jacket, cyborg.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.